Mana: Beyond Belief documentary film collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Mana: Beyond Belief documentary film collection 2000-2004 2000-2003
AFC 2019/001
Friedman, Peter; Manley, Roger; Strange Attractions, Inc.
1,015 items
200 documents in 51 folders: paper.
47 document files in 13 folders: digital; xls, doc, plain text, jpg, pages, pdf.
145 videocassettes (HDCAM): digital.
435 video files: digital; mp4, mov, mxf.
94 sound cassettes (DAT): digital.
94 audio files: digital; wav.
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection consists of moving image and sound footage shot between 2000 and 2003, which led to the documentary film MANA: Beyond Belief (2004). Paper and electronic documents created during production and post-production are also included (logs, translations, shot lists, and notes).
Provenance
Peter Friedman and Roger Manley, Purchase/Gift; 2018.
Accruals
One accrual received in August 2021. All collection materials from the original acquisition and the accrual are described in this finding aid.
Access and Restrictions
The Mana: Beyond Belief documentary film collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Peter Friedman and Roger Manley are known among folklorists and ethnographic filmmakers for their craft. Their various projects (including MANA: Beyond Belief ) have been awarded professional film prizes, grants, and international screenings.
Peter Friedman
Producer/director Peter Friedman has won many of the top awards for documentary film in the USA and Europe, and he has served on the competion juries of major European film festivals. Friedman's films include Wizard of the Strings (1985), Silverlake Life: The View From Here (1993), and Death by Design (1997).
Roger Manley
Producer/director Roger Manley's books, exhibitions, and documentation of the folklife of indigenous peoples have earned him international recognition in the fields of outsider art, anthropology, and photography. His books include Signs and Wonders: Outsider Art Inside North Carolina (1989), The Tree of Life: the Inaugural Exhibition of the American Visionary Art Museum (1996), and Self-Made Worlds: Visionary Folk Art Environments (1997).
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the moving image and sound footage, shot between 2000 and 2003, which led to the documentary film MANA: Beyond Belief (2004). Documents created during production and post-production are also included (logs, translations, shot lists, and notes).
Peter Friedman and Roger Manley describe the project as an "[investigation of] the myriad ways in which people around the world invest objects with special meaning or power. The power of objects is a familiar concept to the Maori people of New Zealand, who call it mana. There is no exact equivalent in other languages, but mana means something like 'prestige.' Objects with mana are as diverse as humanity itself, and may embody many different kinds of power and value--religious, artistic, economic, historical, or personal. But mana itself is universal--all people, all over the world, value or venerate something."
The 114 hours of raw footage depict object veneration in Italy, Japan, Benin, France, the United States, the Navajo Nation, Malaysia, Burma, India, New Zealand, and Germany. The footage encompasses subjects such as: a rare exhibition of the Holy Shroud of Turin; the Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine in Kyoto; vodou ceremonies and The Door of No Return in Ouidah; the holy dirt of Chimayo; Navajo hogan and sweat lodge ceremonies; a modern-day dime museum in Baltimore; the one-year anniversary ceremony held at the ruins of the World Trade Center twin towers in New York city; Hindu idol-anointing in Penang; Shwedagon Pagoda in Rangoon; a Burmese car-blessing shrine; an Indian IT company in Bangalore; several interviews in New Zealand about the Maori concept of mana; fine art analysis in Berlin; and more.
The collection materials are primarily in English and French, with at least 19 additional languages recorded in ambient speech and interviews: Arabic, Burmese, Cantonese, German, Hindi, Hokkien, Italian, Japanese, Kannada, Karen, Malay, Maori, Navajo, Pali, Spanish, Swiss German, Tamil Indian, Vietnamese, and Yoruba.
Arrangement
The Mana: Beyond Belief documentary film collection is organized in 11 series:
Series 1: Mixed Locations
Series 2: Italy
Series 3: Japan
Series 4: Benin
Series 5: France
Series 6: United States
Series 7: Malaysia
Series 8: Burma
Series 9: India
Series 10: New Zealand
Series 11: Germany
Arrangement of series is chronological, according to date of filming. This preserves the filmmakers' chronological tape-numbering system and the multiple cross-references to those numbers in documents. Series 1: Mixed Locations consists of documents which describe multiple filming locations or production as a whole. The remaining 10 series outline the 10 countries in which filming took place; these consist of all manuscript, video, and audio materials which relate to a given location. Materials which depict two locations are listed twice in each relevant series or subseries.
Quoted text comes directly from creators' notes. Geographic names are spelled according to the Library of Congress Name Authority File.
Video tapes include sound. Audio tapes captured higher resolution audio which generally syncs to the same tracks on video. Digital copies of all tapes exist; these are the primary way to access footage, by referencing the Digital File ID listed under each tape in the Container List below. Digital copies of video are available in three sizes: H264 (.mp4), ProRes (.mov), and Preservation (.mov or .mxf). Digital copies of audio are available in one format: (.wav).
Digital manuscript processing included the creation of a PDF/A preservation copy of each digital document in the collection. Preservation copies and original files can be accessed by referencing the Digital Folder IDs in the Container List below.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Coble, Howard, 1931-2015; Coble, Howard, 1931-2015--Interviews.; Dr. Evermor, 1938-2020; Dr. Evermor, 1938-2020--Interviews.; Friedman, Peter; Gopalakrishnan, Kris, 1955-; Gopalakrishnan, Kris, 1955- --Interviews.; Hatahlie, Danny Jim; Hatahlie, Danny Jim--Interviews.; Hetaraka, Te Warihi; Hetaraka, Te Warihi--Interviews.; Kelch, Jan; Kelch, Jan--Interviews.; Kingsley, Nigel Elvis; Kingsley, Nigel Elvis--Interviews.; Laurenze-Landsberg, Claudia; Laurenze-Landsberg, Claudia--Interviews.; Manley, Roger; Medina, Arthur A. (Arthur Angelo); Medina, Arthur A. (Arthur Angelo)--Interviews.; Peri, Malcolm; Peri, Malcolm--Interviews.; Rabinowitch, David; Rabinowitch, David,--Interviews.; Redmustache, Buddy; Redmustache, Buddy--Interviews.; Reimelt, Maria; Reimelt, Maria--Interviews.; Schmidt, Christoph, 1959-; Schmidt, Christoph, 1959- --Interviews.; Zonnie, Kee, 1924-2010; Zonnie, Kee, 1924-2010--Interviews.
Organizations
Chicago Mercantile Exchange.; Gemäldegalerie (Berlin, Germany); Graceland Mansion (Memphis, Tenn.); Inari Jinja (Kyoto, Japan); Infosys Technologies Ltd.; Père-Lachaise (Cemetery: Paris, France); Santuario de Chimayo (Chimayo, N.M.); Strange Attractions, Inc.
Subjects
Blessing and cursing--India--Bangalore.; Buddhist temples.; Curiosities and wonders.; Dime museums--Maryland--Baltimore.; Documentary films--Production and direction.; Elvis Presley impersonators.; Fetishism.; Flags--United States.; Funeral rites and ceremonies--Malaysia--Pulau Pinang (State); Hindu temples.; Hogans--Arizona.; Holy Shroud.; Lowriders.; Mana.; Marae--New Zealand.; Metal sculpture--Wisconsin--Sumpter (Town); Mosques.; Navajo Indians--Rites and ceremonies.; Pagodas--Burma.; Sacred space.; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001--Anniversaries, etc.; Shrines.; Spirituality.; Taoist temples.; Vietnam Veterans Memorial (Washington, D.C.); Vodou--Benin.; Yoruba (African people)--Rites and ceremonies.
Places
Bangalore (India)--Social life and customs.; Cotonou (Benin)--Social life and customs.; Espanola (N.M.)--Social life and customs.; Four Corners Region.; George Town (Pulau Pinang, Malaysia)--Social life and customs.; Kyoto (Japan)--Social life and customs.; Monument Valley (Ariz. and Utah); Navajo Nation, Arizona, New Mexico & Utah--Social life and customs.; Ouidah (Benin)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Mixed Locations
  - Manuscripts
    - Manuscript materials that accompanied videocassettes, circa 2002-09-01 to circa 2002-11-16, 2 pages (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Recording logs, circa 2000-10-20 to circa mid-2003, 25 pages (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Recording log, circa mid-2003, 01_MixedLocations_Recording log; 1 file (.pdf) (Digital-content afc2019001_dc002)
    - Recording logs, circa 2000-10-20 to circa mid-2003, approx. 100 pages (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Translation notes, 2003-04-08, 11 pages (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Translation notes, 2003-06-02 to circa 2004, 01_MixedLocations_Translation notes; 3 files (.doc, .pages) (Digital-content afc2019001_dc002)
    - Notes, correspondence, contacts, circa 2000-10-20 to after circa 2003-02-05, 9 pages (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Correspondence, 2003-02-06, 01_MixedLocations_Correspondence; 1 file (.doc) (Digital-content afc2019001_dc002)
    - Recording logs, 2004-02-02, 01_MixedLocations_Recording logs; 9 files (.xls) (Digital-content afc2019001_dc001)
- Series 2: Italy
  - Turin, October 20-23, 2000
    - Manuscripts
      - Recording logs, circa 2000-10-20, 4 pages (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Translations and transcriptions, circa 2003-04, 76 pages; Italian, English (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 8 pages; "Extèrieurs," "Mass," "Reproduction for blind people," "Shots of the shroud," "Shroud," "int eglise," "Souvenirs Market" (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 1, 2000-10-20, AFC 2019/001: MV001; afc2019001_0001; 49 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 2, 2000-10-20, AFC 2019/001: MV002; afc2019001_0002; 48 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 3, 2000-10-20, AFC 2019/001: MV003; afc2019001_0003; 49 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 4, 2000-10-20 to 2000-10-21, AFC 2019/001: MV004; afc2019001_0004; 49 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 5, 2000-10-21, AFC 2019/001: MV005; afc2019001_0005; 48 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 6, 2000-10-21, AFC 2019/001: MV006; afc2019001_0006; 49 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 7, 2000-10-21, AFC 2019/001: MV007; afc2019001_0007; 49 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 8, 2000-10-22, AFC 2019/001: MV008; afc2019001_0008; 50 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 9, 2000-10-22, AFC 2019/001: MV009; afc2019001_0009; 50 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - HDCAM Tape 10, 2000-10-22, AFC 2019/001: MV010; afc2019001_0010; 49 min.; Holy Shroud, city and street views
      - HDCAM Tape 11, 2000-10-23, AFC 2019/001: MV011; afc2019001_0011; 7 min.; City and street views
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 1, 2000-10-20, AFC 2019/001: SR001; afc2019001_DAT0001; 50 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - DAT Tape 2, 2000-10-20, AFC 2019/001: SR002; afc2019001_DAT0002; 1 hr. 0 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - DAT Tape 3, 2000-10-20 to 2000-10-21, AFC 2019/001: SR003; afc2019001_DAT0003; 1 hr. 0 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - DAT Tape 4, 2000-10-21 to 2000-10-22, AFC 2019/001: SR004; afc2019001_DAT0004; 1 hr. 9 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - DAT Tape 5, 2000-10-22, AFC 2019/001: SR005; afc2019001_DAT0005; 1 hr. 37 min.; Cappella della Sindone (Chapel of the Holy Shroud), Duomo di Torino (Turin Cathedral), Holy Shroud
      - DAT Tape 6, 2000-10-23, AFC 2019/001: SR006; afc2019001_DAT0006; 25 min.; City and street sounds
- Series 3: Japan
  - Kyoto, March 29-April 2, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Translations, circa 2003-04, This item is also listed in Series 3, Tokyo.; 15 pages; English, French (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Translations, 2003-04-16, 03_Japan_Kyoto_Translations; 1 file (.doc); English (Digital-content afc2019001_dc002)
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 9 pages; "cherry B. Day," "cherry B. Night," "Fox Shrine" (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 12, 2002-03-29, AFC 2019/001: MV012; afc2019001_0012; 47 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - HDCAM Tape 13, 2002-03-29, AFC 2019/001: MV013; afc2019001_0013 (preservation file is .mxf format); 50 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - HDCAM Tape 14, 2002-03-30, AFC 2019/001: MV014; afc2019001_0014; 47 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - HDCAM Tape 15, 2002-03-30, AFC 2019/001: MV015; afc2019001_0015; 46 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - HDCAM Tape 16, 2002-03-30 to 2002-03-31, AFC 2019/001: MV016; afc2019001_0016; 48 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing), Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine)
      - HDCAM Tape 17, 2002-03-31, AFC 2019/001: MV017; afc2019001_0017; 48 min.; Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine)
      - HDCAM Tape 18, 2002-03-31 to 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV018; This item is also listed in Series 3, Tokyo.; afc2019001_0018; 49 min.; Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine), Shibuya scramble crossing
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 12, 2002-03-29, AFC 2019/001: SR012; afc2019001_DAT0012; 56 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - DAT Tape 13, 2002-03-29 to 2002-03-30, AFC 2019/001: SR013; afc2019001_DAT0013; 58 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - DAT Tape 14, 2002-03-30, AFC 2019/001: SR014; afc2019001_DAT0014; 1 hr. 2 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - DAT Tape 15, 2002-03-30, AFC 2019/001: SR015; afc2019001_DAT0015; 53 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing)
      - DAT Tape 16, 2002-03-30 to 2002-03-31, AFC 2019/001: SR016; afc2019001_DAT0016; 1 hr. 4 min.; Maruyama Park, sakura (cherry blossoms), hanami (flower viewing), Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine)
      - DAT Tape 17, 2002-03-31, AFC 2019/001: SR017; afc2019001_DAT0017; 58 min.; Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine)
      - DAT Tape 18, 2002-03-31, AFC 2019/001: SR018; afc2019001_DAT0018; 25 min.; Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine)
  - Tokyo, March 31-April 2, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Translations, circa 2003-04, This item is also listed in Series 3, Kyoto.; 15 pages; English (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 6 pages; "Tokyo streets," "Marché en journée," "Poisson frais," "Poisson surgelé nuit" (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 18, 2002-03-31 to 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV018; This item is also listed in Series 3, Kyoto.; afc2019001_0018; 49 min.; Inari Jinja (Fushimi Inari Taisha shrine), Shibuya scramble crossing
      - HDCAM Tape 19, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV019; afc2019001_0019; 47 min.; Shibuya scramble crossing, Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna)
      - HDCAM Tape 20, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV020; afc2019001_0020; 47 min.; Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna)
      - HDCAM Tape 21, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV021; afc2019001_0021; 48 min.; Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna), city and street views
      - HDCAM Tape 22, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: MV022; afc2019001_0022; 16 min.; Busy crosswalk
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 19, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: SR019; afc2019001_DAT0019; 52 min.; Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna)
      - DAT Tape 20, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: SR020; afc2019001_DAT0020; 1 hr. 8 min.; Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna)
      - DAT Tape 21, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: SR021; afc2019001_DAT0021; 34 min.; Tsukiji fish market, auction of maguro (blue fin tuna), city and street sounds
      - DAT Tape 22, 2002-04-02, AFC 2019/001: SR022; afc2019001_DAT0022; 24 min.; Busy crosswalk
- Series 4: Benin
  - Unidentified village, July 1, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 1 page; "Voodoo Village" (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 25, 2002-07-01, AFC 2019/001: MV025; afc2019001_0025; 48 min.; Screen test, Vodou ceremony
      - HDCAM Tape 26, 2002-07-01, AFC 2019/001: MV026; afc2019001_0026; 48 min.; Vodou ceremony
      - HDCAM Tape 27, 2002-07-01 to 2002-07-02, AFC 2019/001: MV027; This item is also listed in Series 4, Cotonou.; afc2019001_0027; 37 min.; Village views, Vodou market
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 25, 2002-07-01, AFC 2019/001: SR025; afc2019001_DAT0025; 1 hr. 5 min.; Vodou ceremony
  - Cotonou, July 1-6, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 3 pages; "Voodoo Market," "divers rues et activités" (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 27, 2002-07-01 to 2002-07-02, AFC 2019/001: MV027; This item is also listed in Series 4, Unidentified village.; afc2019001_0027; 37 min.; Village views, Vodou market
      - HDCAM Tape 28, 2002-07-02, AFC 2019/001: MV028; afc2019001_0028; 49 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians)
      - HDCAM Tape 29, 2002-07-02 to 2002-07-03, AFC 2019/001: MV029; This item is also listed in Series 4, Ouidah.; afc2019001_0029; 49 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians), Door of No Return
      - HDCAM Tape 34, 2002-07-04 to 2002-07-06, AFC 2019/001: MV034; This item is also listed in Series 4, Ouidah.; afc2019001_0034; 49 min.; Egungun ceremony, textiles, city and street views
      - HDCAM Tape 35, 2002-07-06 to circa 2002-07-09, AFC 2019/001: MV035; afc2019001_0035; 30 min.; City and street views
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 26, 2002-07-01 to 2002-07-02, AFC 2019/001: SR026; afc2019001_DAT0026; 1 hr. 7 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians)
      - DAT Tape 27, 2002-07-02, AFC 2019/001: SR027; afc2019001_DAT0027; 1 hr. 8 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians)
      - DAT Tape 28, 2002-07-02 to 2002-07-03, AFC 2019/001: SR028; This item is also listed in Series 4, Ouidah.; afc2019001_DAT0028; 1 hr. 6 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians), Door of No Return
      - DAT Tape 32, 2002-07-04 to 2002-07-06, AFC 2019/001: SR032; This item is also listed in Series 4, Ouidah.; afc2019001_DAT0032; 1 hr. 6 min.; Egungun ceremony, textiles, city and street sounds
      - DAT Tape 33, 2002-07-06 to 2002-07-09, AFC 2019/001: SR033; afc2019001_DAT0033; 1 hr. 7 min.; City and street sounds
  - Ouidah, July 2-6, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Translations and transcriptions, circa 2003-04, 13 pages; [Yoruba?], French (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 5 pages; "Slave beach," "Revenants" (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 29, 2002-07-02 to 2002-07-03, AFC 2019/001: MV029; This item is also listed in Series 4, Cotonou.; afc2019001_0029; 49 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians), Door of No Return
      - HDCAM Tape 30, 2002-07-03, AFC 2019/001: MV030; afc2019001_0030; 47 min.; Door of No Return
      - HDCAM Tape 31, 2002-07-03 to 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: MV031; afc2019001_0031; 49 min.; Egungun prayer and ceremony
      - HDCAM Tape 32, 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: MV032; afc2019001_0032; 49 min.; Egungun ceremony
      - HDCAM Tape 33, 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: MV033; afc2019001_0033; 49 min.; Egungun ceremony
      - HDCAM Tape 34, 2002-07-04 to 2002-07-06, AFC 2019/001: MV034; This item is also listed in Series 4, Cotonou.; afc2019001_0034; 49 min.; Egungun ceremony, textiles, city and street views
    - Sound Recordings
      - DAT Tape 28, 2002-07-02 to 2002-07-03, AFC 2019/001: SR028; This item is also listed in Series 4, Cotonou.; afc2019001_DAT0028; 1 hr. 6 min.; Zangbeto (community guardians), Door of No Return
      - DAT Tape 29, 2002-07-03 to 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: SR029; afc2019001_DAT0029; 1 hr. 5 min.; Egungun prayer and ceremony
      - DAT Tape 30, 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: SR030; afc2019001_DAT0030; 1 hr. 7 min.; Egungun ceremony
      - DAT Tape 31, 2002-07-04, AFC 2019/001: SR031; afc2019001_DAT0031; 1 hr. 5 min.; Egungun ceremony
      - DAT Tape 32, 2002-07-04 to 2002-07-06, AFC 2019/001: SR032; This item is also listed in Series 4, Cotonou.; afc2019001_DAT0032; 1 hr. 6 min.; Egungun ceremony, textiles, city and street sounds
- Series 5: France
  - Paris, July 9, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 4 pages; "Jim Morrisson," "Kardec+cimetière" (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 36, 2002-07-09, AFC 2019/001: MV036; afc2019001_0036; 48 min.; Père-Lachaise cemetery, Allan Kardec's tomb
      - HDCAM Tape 37, 2002-07-09, AFC 2019/001: MV037; afc2019001_0037; 48 min.; Père-Lachaise cemetery, Jim Morrison's grave
      - HDCAM Tape 38, 2002-07-09, AFC 2019/001: MV038; afc2019001_0038; 38 min.; Père-Lachaise cemetery, Jim Morrison's grave
- Series 6: United States
  - Memphis (Tenn.), August 14-17, 2002
    - Manuscripts
      - Translation and transcription, circa 2003-04, 6 pages; Swiss German, English (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Translation and transcription, 2003-04-14, 06_USA_Memphis_Translation and transcription; 2 files (.doc); Swiss German, English (Digital-content afc2019001_dc002)
      - Post-production documentation, 2003-10-14, 14 pages; "à classer?," "Attente soir+procession," "Concours chant sosies," "Elvis-Parking," "Graceland jour," "Hotel inscriptions concours," "PHOTOS" (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Moving Images
      - HDCAM Tape 39, 2002-08-14, AFC 2019/001: MV039; afc2019001_0039; 49 min.; 25th anniversary of Elvis Presley's death, Elvis Presley impersonators
      - HDCAM Tape 40, 2002-08-14, AFC 2019/001: MV040; afc2019001_0040; 49 min.; 25th anniversary of Elvis Presley's death, Elvis Presley impersonators
      - HDCAM Tape 41, 2002-08-14 to 2002-08-15, AFC 2019/001: MV041; afc2019001_0041; 50 min.; 25th anniversary of Elvis Presley's death, Elvis Presley impersonators, Graceland Mansion, Elvis Presley's grave
      - HDCAM Tape 42, 2002-08-15, AFC 2019/001: MV042; afc2019001_0042; 49 min.; 25th anniversary of Elvis Presley's death, Graceland Mansion, Elvis Presley's grave
      - HDCAM Tape 43, 2002-08-15, AFC 2019/001: MV043; afc2019001_0043; 49 min.; 25th anniversary of Elvis Presley's death, Graceland Mansion